The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Last lecture on sorting.
教授：关于分类的最后一次演讲。
Yay.
好极了。
And it's one of the coolest lectures on sorting,
这是有关分类的最酷的演讲之一，
I would say.
我会说。
We're going to talk about linear-time sorting, when it's
我们将讨论线性时间排序
possible and when it's not possible,
可能，而当不可能时，
and this lecture sort of follows the tried and tested
这堂课遵循了久经考验的
mathematical structure which is theorem, proof, counterexample.
定理，证明，反例的数学结构。
So we're going to start with a theorem which
因此，我们将从一个定理开始
is that sorting requires n lg n time at least in the worst case
至少在最坏的情况下，排序需要n lg n次
and we're going to then prove that in fact, you can get away
然后我们将证明事实是，您可以逃脱
with linear time sometimes.
与线性时间有时。
Both of these terms are correct, but they're slightly
这两个词都是正确的，但它们略有不同
different models of computation.
不同的计算模型。
Remember models of computation from lecture two?
还记得第二课的计算模型吗？
So we're going to talk about a new model of computation, which
因此，我们将讨论一种新的计算模型
we've sort of been using for most algorithms lately,
我们最近一直在使用大多数算法，
called the comparison model.
称为比较模型。
And it's a model of computations that's
这是一个计算模型
really useful for proving lower bounds which
对于证明下界非常有用
we haven't done much of yet.
我们还没有做很多事情。
We're going to prove two very simple lower bounds.
我们将证明两个非常简单的下界。
One is that searching requires lg n time.
一种是搜索需要lg n时间。
This is basically binary search is optimal.
这基本上是二进制搜索的最佳选择。
And the other is that sorting requires n lg n time.
另一个是排序需要n lg n个时间。
This is that merge sort is optimal.
这是合并排序是最佳的。
And then we're going to break outside of that comparison
然后，我们将超出该比较范围
model, work in a different model of computation, our more
模型，在不同的计算模型中工作，我们的更多
usual RAM model, and show that in certain situations,
通常的RAM模型，并表明在某些情况下，
we can get linear time.
我们可以得到线性时间。
So that's the plan.
这就是计划。
Let's start with this comparison model.
让我们从这个比较模型开始。
So the idea in the comparison model
所以比较模型中的想法
is to restrict what kind of operations
是限制哪种操作
we can do to be comparisons.
我们可以做个比较。
It's very straightforward.
非常简单。
All input items are black boxes, you could say,
您可以说所有输入项都是黑匣子，
in that you don't really know what they are.
因为您真的不知道它们是什么。
And a formal notion of black boxes
和黑匣子的正式概念
is something we talked about last class
这是我们上课时谈到的
at the end, abstract data type.
最后是抽象数据类型。
So it's a data structure, if you will.
如果可以的话，这是一个数据结构。
Every item that you're given is a data structure.
您得到的每个项目都是一个数据结构。
You want to sort them.
您想对它们进行排序。
And the data structure supports a single operation
并且数据结构支持单个操作
which is compared to another one.
与另一个相比。
Only operation allowed-- I guess I should say plural actually--
仅允许操作-我想我应该说复数-
are comparisons.
是比较。
I'm going to be nice and I'll let you do less than, less than
我会变得很好，我会让你做不到，做不到
or equal to, greater than, whatever.
等于或大于等于任何东西
I guess there's only one other.
我猜只有一个。
Well, there's two more, greater than or equal to and equals.
好吧，还有两个，大于或等于和等于。
So you can do all the usual comparisons.
因此，您可以进行所有常规比较。
You get a binary answer, yes or no,
您得到一个二进制答案，是或否，
and those the only operations you're given.
以及您获得的唯一操作。
And basically the last four lectures
基本上是最后四堂课
have all been about algorithms in this model.
都与该模型中的算法有关。
So merge sort, it moves items around.
因此，合并排序可以移动项目。
It's changing pointers to items, but the only way
它正在改变指向项目的指针，但这是唯一的方法
it manipulates items or evaluates them
它操纵或评估项目
is to compare one against the other.
是将一个与另一个进行比较。
Heaps and heaps sort also only compare.
堆和堆的排序也只能比较。
Binary search trees only compare.
二进制搜索树仅进行比较。
Everything we've been seeing so far is about comparisons.
到目前为止，我们所看到的一切都是关于比较的。
And so all the algorithms we've seen so far are in this model
因此，到目前为止，我们看到的所有算法都在该模型中
and we're going to prove that they are optimal in this model.
我们将证明它们在此模型中是最佳的。
That's the plan.
那是计划。
I should also define the cost of an algorithm.
我还应该定义算法的成本。
Time cost is just going to be the number of comparisons.
时间成本只是比较的次数。
This is the weird part, I guess, of the model.
我猜这是模型的怪异部分。
So in everything we've done so far, we've been in, I guess,
因此，到目前为止，在我们所做的所有事情中，我们都参与了
pointer machine or RAM, either way.
指针机或RAM，无论哪种方式。
We've been showing binary search trees or AVL trees,
我们一直在显示二进制搜索树或AVL树，
you can do order lg n time, in the regular notion of time.
您可以按照常规的时间顺序对lg n时间进行排序。
But in particular they do order lg n comparisons.
但尤其是它们确实会进行lg n比较。
And what we're going to show on the-- this
而我们将要展示的是
is only interesting from a lower bound perspective--
仅从下限的角度来看很有趣-
we're going to show that even if you just count comparisons,
我们将证明即使您只计算比较，
you can do whatever other crazy things you want.
您可以做任何您想做的其他疯狂事情。
You need lg n time to search.
您需要lg n的时间进行搜索。
You need n lg n time to sort.
您需要n lg n的时间进行排序。
So that's our goal.
这就是我们的目标。
So to prove that we're going to introduce
因此，为了证明我们将要介绍
the notion of a decision tree.
决策树的概念。
So the idea is the following: if we know that our algorithms are
因此，想法如下：如果我们知道我们的算法是
only comparing items, we can actually sort of draw
仅比较项目，我们实际上可以得出
all the possible things that an algorithm could do,
算法可以做的所有可能的事情，
so any comparison algorithm.
所以任何比较算法。
So this focusing in on comparisons
因此，本着重于比较
lets us take a tree perspective of what our algorithm does--
让我们从树的角度来了解算法的作用-
all possible comparisons and their outcomes
所有可能的比较及其结果
and the resulting answer.
以及得到的答案。
I think this would be a lot clearer if we
我认为如果我们
look at an example-- binary search,
看一个例子-二进制搜索
how you search a simple algorithm.
您如何搜索简单的算法。
Look at the middle compared to the item you're
看看中间与您所要的项目相比
searching for go left or go right.
搜索向左或向右。
And our idea-- I didn't write it here--
我们的想法-我没有在这里写-
is to look at a particular value of n,
是看n的特定值，
n being the size of your problem, so binary search,
n是您问题的大小，所以二进制搜索，
you're searching among n items for another item.
您正在n个项目中搜索另一个项目。
And I'm going to keep it simple, n equals three.
我将保持简单，n等于3。
I think I'm going to go a little wide, use the whole board.
我想我要扩大一点，用整个木板。
So n equals 3 we've got array, say
所以n等于3我们有数组
index turning at zero-- pretty simple binary search-- look
索引为零-非常简单的二进制搜索-外观
in the middle, go left or go right.
在中间，向左或向右走。
But I'm going to write out this algorithm explicitly to say,
但是我要明确写出这个算法，说：
all right, first thing I do is compare is A 1 less than x?
好吧，我要做的第一件事就是比较A是否小于x？
That's in all cases, no matter what
在所有情况下，无论如何
the array is as long as n equals three,
只要n等于三，数组就可以
this is the first operation you do.
这是您要做的第一项操作。
The answer is either yes or no.
答案是是或否。
If the answer is no, that means x is less than or equal to A 1,
如果答案为否，则意味着x小于或等于A 1，
so it's to the left.
所以在左边
Then we compare with A 0.
然后我们与A 0比较。
Is A 0 less than x?
A 0小于x吗？
Answer is either yes or no.
答案是是或否。
If the answer is no, we're kind of done.
如果答案是否定的，那么我们就完成了。
We know that x is over here or it might actually
我们知道x在这里，或者实际上
be equal to A 0.
等于A 0。
If you want to figure out whether it's
如果你想弄清楚是否
equal or less than, there will be one more step.
等于或小于，将再有一个步骤。
But I'll just stop it here.
但是我只是在这里停下来。
We'll say, well in this case, x is less than or equal to A 0.
我们可以说，在这种情况下，x小于或等于A 0。
I'm going to put it in a box, say that's done
我要把它放在盒子里，说完了
where the circles are the decisions.
圈子在哪里决定。
OK?
好？
If the answer is yes-- there's no to this question, yes
如果答案是肯定的-这个问题没有答案
to this question-- then you know that x falls in between here.
这个问题-那么您知道x介于此处。
Probably need a wider box for this.
可能需要一个更大的盒子。
So we have A 0 is less than x-- that was the yes to this--
所以我们有一个A 0小于x-这是肯定的-
and the note of this means that x is less than or equal to A 1,
并且注意，这意味着x小于或等于A 1，
and so we basically identified where x fits.
因此，我们基本上确定了x适合的位置。
It's in between those two values,
在这两个值之间
possibly equal to this one.
可能等于这个。
Again, one more comparison, you could figure that out.
同样，再进行一次比较，您可以弄清楚这一点。
And then if x is to the right of A 1, so this is true,
然后如果x在A 1的右边，那么这是真的，
then we check x against A 2 and the answer is either no or yes.
然后我们针对A 2来检查x，答案是否定的。
And in the no case-- well I've conveniently laid things out
而且在任何情况下-我都已经很方便地布置了东西
here, it's sequential-- in the yes case, x is bigger than A 2
这里是顺序的-是的，x大于A 2
so it's outside the array.
所以它在数组之外
It's to the right.
在右边。
That's the answer.
那就是答案。
Set.
组。
Yeah.
是的
And in the other case, it's in between A 1 and A 2.
在另一种情况下，它介于A 1和A 2之间。
It's a tedious process to write out an algorithm like this
编写这样的算法是一个繁琐的过程
because a binary search-- it's not so bad-- but if you tried
因为二进制搜索-还不错-但如果您尝试过
to write a sorting algorithm out like this
写出这样的排序算法
where the answers are down the bottom, here's
答案在最底层，这里是
the sorted order, and all the comparisons you do here,
排序的顺序，以及您在此处所做的所有比较，
the tree will actually be of exponential size.
该树实际上将具有指数大小。
So you don't actually want to represent an algorithm
所以你实际上并不想代表一个算法
like this unless you're just trying to analyze it.
除非您只是试图对其进行分析，否则不会这样。
But it's nice to think of an algorithm this way
但是以这种方式想到一个算法真是太好了
because you see all possible executions all at once.
因为您一次看到所有可能的执行。
Let me talk about some features of this tree
让我说说这棵树的一些特点
versus the algorithm.
与算法。
So every internal node-- actually,
所以每个内部节点-实际上，
I'm going to go over here.
我要去这里。
So we have a decision tree and we
所以我们有一个决策树，我们
have an algorithm that decision tree represents.
有一个决策树代表的算法。
And so when we have an internal node in the decision tree,
因此，当我们在决策树中有一个内部节点时，
that corresponds to a binary decision in the algorithm.
对应于算法中的二元决策。
In this case, we're only looking at comparisons.
在这种情况下，我们只看比较。
Slight technical detail, decision trees
少量技术细节，决策树
are a little more general than comparisons.
比比较要笼统一些。
Could be any binary decision here and everything I say
可能是任何二进制决定，我所说的一切
will be true about any binary decision you make.
您所做的任何二元决策都是正确的。
Comparisons are the ones we kind of care about
比较是我们所关心的
because all of our algorithms are doing that.
因为我们所有的算法都在这样做。
And then a leaf in this tree corresponds to-- it stores
然后这棵树上的一片叶子对应于-它存储
or it represents that you've found the answer.
或代表您已找到答案。
Maybe I'll say found.
也许我会说找到。
When the algorithm terminates, returns some answer
当算法终止时，返回一些答案
to the problem, that's what we write down here.
问题所在，那就是我们在这里写下的内容。
Here's where x is in this array and, yeah, we're done.
这是x在此数组中的位置，是的，我们完成了。
What else do we have?
我们还有什么？
Here's some puzzles for you.
这是给您的难题。
If I just wanted to look at a single execution
如果我只想看一次执行
of the algorithm, what does that correspond to in the tree?
的算法，在树中对应什么？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Going from the root all the way down to the leaf.
听众：从根一直到叶子。
PROFESSOR: Going from the root down to a leaf.
教授：从根到叶。
This is what I normally call a root-to-leaf path, technically
从技术上讲，这就是我通常所说的从根到叶的路径
a downward root-to-leaf path.
向下的从根到叶的路径。
How about the running time of that execution?
该执行的运行时间如何？
How long does it take?
多久时间？
Keep going?
继续？
AUDIENCE: Lg n.
听众：Lg n。
PROFESSOR: Lg n in binary search, but in general.
教授：在二进制搜索中为Lg n，但一般而言。
AUDIENCE: The length of that path.
听众：路径的长度。
PROFESSOR: The length of that path.
教授：该路径的长度。
Yeah.
是的
Got to make sure we get n cases right but I think it's correct,
要确保我们正确处理n个案件，但我认为这是正确的，
so if here is an execution of the algorithm, when x happens
因此，如果这是算法的执行，则x发生时
to be between A 0 and A 1, we do one comparison here,
在A 0和A 1之间，我们在这里做一个比较，
a second comparison here, and then we're done.
在这里进行第二次比较，然后完成。
So the cost was two and indeed the length of this path is two.
因此，成本为2，而这条路径的长度实际上为2。
So it works out, no off-by-one errors.
这样就可以解决问题，不会出现一一错误的情况。
All right, now exciting one for us,
好吧，现在让我们激动不已，
what we care about all the time in this class
我们在课堂上一直在关心什么
is worst-case running time.
是最坏的运行时间。
This is a feature of the entire algorithm.
这是整个算法的功能。
What is the worst-case running time of a given decision tree?
给定决策树的最坏情况下运行时间是多少？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: The height of the root, the height of the tree.
听众：根的高度，树的高度。
PROFESSOR: The height of the root also called
教授：根的高度也称为
the height of the tree.
树的高度。
Yep.
是的
Or the depth of the deepest leaf, whatever.
或最深的叶子的深度，随便。
So in this case all the leaves have the same level,
因此，在这种情况下，所有叶子都具有相同的水平，
but in general we care about the overall height.
但总的来说，我们关心整体高度。
How many levels in this tree are there?
这棵树上有多少层？
It's the number of levels minus one, technically.
从技术上讲，它是级别数减去一。
But the length of longest root-to-leaf path
但是最长的根到叶路径的长度
is the definition of height.
是高度的定义。
Here it's two.
这是两个。
In general we know for binary search it's lg n,
一般来说，对于二进制搜索，我们知道它是lg n，
but given an arbitrary decision tree,
但给定任意决策树，
we just have to figure out what the height of the tree
我们只需要弄清楚树的高度是多少
is and we'll figure out the worst-case running time.
是的，我们将找出最坏情况下的运行时间。
So this is why decision trees are interesting.
这就是为什么决策树很有趣的原因。
Not because it means they're pretty I guess, but the reason
我猜不是因为这意味着它们很漂亮，而是原因
they're going to be useful is we have this kind of hard question
他们会很有用，如果我们有这样一个难题
which is how much time do you need to solve a problem?
您需要多少时间解决问题？
And we're translating it into how low can you
我们正在将其转化为您能达到的最低水平
make your tree, which is a problem we know a lot about.
做你的树，这是我们非常了解的问题。
Trees are pretty simple.
树木很简单。
These are binary trees.
这些是二叉树。
They're rooted, and so we know lots of good things.
他们扎根，所以我们知道很多好事。
So let's prove some lower bounds.
因此，让我们证明一些下限。
So I claim that for searching-- maybe I
所以我声称是为了搜寻-也许我
should define the problem a little more formally--
应该更正式地定义问题-
I want to claim a lg n lower bound.
我想声明一个lg n下界。
So let's say for searching I have n preprocessed items.
因此，假设搜索有n个预处理项目。
Then finding a given item among them in the comparison model,
然后在比较模型中找到其中的给定项目，
so all you're allowed to do are compare items and other stuff,
所以您所要做的就是比较商品和其他东西，
but the only things you're allowed to do with the items
但是您唯一可以做的事情
is compare them.
比较它们。
Requires omega lg n comparisons in the worst case.
在最坏的情况下，需要进行欧米茄lg n比较。
It's kind of tedious to write down these theorems,
写下这些定理有点繁琐，
but for our first lower bounds, I
但是对于我们的第一个下界
thought I'd be super explicit.
以为我会超级露骨。
I mentioned here that the items are preprocessed
我在这里提到这些物品已经过预处理
to mean you could do whatever you want the items ahead
意味着你可以做任何你想做的事
of time, that's for free.
时间是免费的。
So I can sort them in particular,
所以我可以对它们进行特别排序
which lets me do binary search.
这让我进行二进制搜索。
I could build them into an AVL tree, could do lots of things,
我可以将它们构建到AVL树中，可以做很多事情，
but no matter what I do to find another item takes lg n time.
但是无论我怎么做才能找到另一个项目需要lg n的时间。
Can someone tell me why?
有人可以告诉我为什么吗？
Who doesn't have the lecture notes right in front them,
谁没有前面的讲义，
that would make it easy.
这将使其变得容易。
This is a little more interesting,
这有点有趣，
but we had all the tools at our disposal now.
但是我们现在拥有所有工具。
We want to show that this at least lg n.
我们想证明这至少是lg n。
Why?
为什么？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] have a no or yes, right?
听众：[听不清]是或否，对吗？
So it's--
所以是 -
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
AUDIENCE: --omega lg n tree.
听众：--omega lg n树。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
At each step, we only have a no or yes.
在每一步中，我们只有否或是。
That's a binary tree.
那是一棵二叉树。
So that makes you think lg n.
因此，您会想到lg n。
AUDIENCE: That's possible, it could be lg n.
听众：有可能，lg n。
PROFESSOR: Maximum actually could be arbitrarily large.
教授：最大值实际上可以任意大。
You could do a linear search and the height will be m.
您可以进行线性搜索，高度为m。
We care about the minimum of course.
我们关心最低限度的课程。
Why does it have to be-- why does the height of a tree
为什么必须-为什么树的高度
have to be at least lg n?
必须至少为lg n？
There's one more thing we need to say.
我们还需要说一件事。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: The tree has to contain all possible--
听众：树必须包含所有可能的-
PROFESSOR: Because the tree has to contain
教授：因为树必须包含
all possible-- answers, let's say.
假设一切皆有可能。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，完全正确。
I think that's worth a pillow.
我认为这值得一个枕头。
See if I can do this-- oh!
看看我能不能做-哦！
Ouch.
哎哟。
I knew it was only a matter of time.
我知道这只是时间问题。
Sorry.
抱歉。
I'll pay you later.
我待会儿付给你。
Damages.
损害赔偿。
At least I didn't hit a laptop or something.
至少我没有打笔记本电脑之类的东西。
All right, so decision tree is binary--
好吧，决策树是二进制的
that was the first thing-- and it
那是第一件事-而且
must have at least n leaves, one for each answer.
必须至少有n个叶子，每个答案一个。
At least.
至少。
Now, at the leaf you have to know what the answer is,
现在，在叶子上，您必须知道答案是什么，
but there may be many leaves that have the same answer.
但是可能有很多叶子有相同的答案。
That's possible.
有可能
And indeed that will happen not for binary search
确实，二进制搜索不会发生这种情况
but typical algorithm.
但是典型的算法。
There's multiple paths to get the same answer,
可以通过多种途径获得相同的答案，
so there may be more leaves than n.
所以叶子可能比n多。
And in fact, if you want to know this kind of thing, where
实际上，如果您想知道这种事情，
x fits in this perspective, there's n plus 1 answers.
x适合这个观点，有n个加1个答案。
If you want to know is it equal or is
如果您想知道它是否相等
it strictly between two things there's 2n plus 1 answers.
严格来说，两件事之间是2n加1的答案。
But in all cases, there's at least n answers
但在所有情况下，至少有n个答案
and that's all I need.
这就是我所需要的。
In particular there's-- say x exactly matches one
特别是-说x完全匹配一个
of the given items-- there's n items--
给定项目中的n个
so you need to have at least n leaves.
因此您至少需要n个叶子。
Maybe have more, I don't care.
也许还有更多，我不在乎。
But it I have a binary tree with at least n leaves,
但是我有一棵至少有n个叶子的二叉树，
the height has to be at least lg n.
高度必须至少为lg n。
We're done.
大功告成
The height is the worst-case running time.
高度是最坏情况下的运行时间。
Super, super easy proof.
超级，超级容易证明。
So easy, it's never been taught in 006 before.
如此简单，它从未在006中被教导过。
But I think it's a good warm up for the next one which
但是我认为接下来的那场比赛是一个很好的热身
is sorting.
正在排序。
Sorting is really the same thing.
排序实际上是同一回事。
It's not going to be any harder except that it's a little more
除了增加一点点，它不会变得更困难
math but really not much more.
数学，但实际上不多。
So now we know-- we just proved two useful facts--
所以现在我们知道-我们只证明了两个有用的事实-
one is that binary search is optimal in a comparison model,
一个是二进制搜索在比较模型中是最佳的，
the other is that binary search trees are actually a good way
另一个是二进制搜索树实际上是一个好方法
to solve a problem.
解决问题。
If your goal is to solve search and all you're allowed to do
如果您的目标是解决搜索问题，并且您被允许做的一切
is comparisons, then you need lg n time.
是比较，那么您需要lg n时间。
And so the search or next larger or next smaller, predecessor,
因此，搜寻或下一个较大或下一个较小的前身，
successor, in binary search trees
后继项，在二进制搜索树中
need to take at least lg n time.
需要至少花费lg n次。
No matter how you do it, even if you don't use a tree.
无论您怎么做，即使您不使用树也是如此。
So this justifies why binary search trees are interesting,
因此，这证明了为什么二进制搜索树很有趣，
because again the comparison model, that's
因为同样是比较模型
the best you can hope to do.
您所希望做到的最好。
So that's comforting.
因此令人感到安慰。
That's why I like lower bounds and theoretical computer
这就是为什么我喜欢下限和理论计算机
science in general because you know when you're done,
科学，因为您知道自己完成的时间，
at least in a given model.
至少在给定的模型中。
Whenever-- we're never actually done,
每当-我们从未真正完成过，
because we can always change the model.
因为我们可以随时更改模型。
At least we understand the limitations of comparisons.
至少我们了解比较的局限性。
So for sorting, we claim a lower bound of n lg n.
因此，为了进行排序，我们要求n lg n的下限。
You've heard n lg n a zillion times.
您已听过无数次。
You probably know this is true, but now we
您可能知道这是真的，但是现在我们
actually get to prove that it's true.
真正证明这是真的。
So we just follow the same strategy.
因此，我们只是遵循相同的策略。
Decision tree is binary.
决策树是二进制的。
The question is how many leaves does it have to have?
问题是它必须有几片叶子？
So for sorting-- I didn't draw up an example--
因此，为了排序-我没有画一个例子-
I'm not going to draw an example of sorting
我不会举一个排序的例子
because the trees get ginormous.
因为树木变得巨大。
Right?
对？
Because of the depth is n log n, the height is n log n,
由于深度为n log n，高度为n log n，
then there's binary branching everywhere.
然后到处都有二进制分支。
That's a lot of nodes.
有很多节点。
Two to the n lg n is big.
n lg n是2。
More than two to the n even, so it's
n等于2以上，所以
hard to draw a picture even for n equals 3.
即使n等于3也很难画画。
You can do it.
你能行的。
People have done it.
人们已经做到了。
I don't want to.
我不想
I'm lazy.
我很懒。
But the internal nodes look just the same.
但是内部节点看起来是一样的。
You're comparing two items, A I verses
您正在比较两个项目，人工智能经文
A J. I'll just draw the generic version.
J。我只画通用版本。
You have A I less than A J, question mark.
您的AI小于AJ，问号。
And then you'll have a no and a yes.
然后，您将得到一个否定和一个是。
So that's what a typical comparison looks like.
这就是典型的比较。
Swaps don't appear here, because we're just
掉期没有出现在这里，因为我们只是
looking at the comparisons.
看比较。
And then when you get down to a leaf, a leaf--
然后当你跌倒一片叶子时，一片叶子-
this is the interesting part-- the leaf will look like this.
这是有趣的部分-叶子看起来像这样。
Well I took the original A 5 and that turned out
好吧，我拿了原始的A 5，结果
to be the smallest element.
成为最小的元素。
Then-- maybe I'll write it this way--
然后-也许我会这样写-
then I have A 7, that turned out to be the next smallest
然后我有A 7，结果倒数第二
element, then A 1 then A 0, whatever.
元素，然后是A 1然后是A 0，无论如何。
Hey, right at the end, somehow you know the sorted order
嘿，到最后，以某种方式知道排序顺序
and you can just write it down.
你可以写下来
We're not charging for this.
我们不为此收费。
We're only charging for comparisons.
我们只收取比较费用。
So however, maybe you've done swaps,
因此，也许您已经完成了交换，
in the end you know what the final order is
最后，您知道最终的订单是什么
and so you just write it down.
所以你就把它写下来
And your goal is to make enough comparisons that you figure out
您的目标是进行足够的比较以找出
what the sorted order is.
什么是排序顺序。
We claim the number of comparisons
我们要求比较的数量
here has to be at least n lg n.
这里必须至少为n lg n。
OK, why?
好为什么
Because the decision tree is binary and the number of leaves
因为决策树是二进制的，叶子数
has to be at least the number of possible answers.
必须至少是可能答案的数量。
Could be more because each answer could appear
可能更多，因为每个答案都可能出现
in several leaves and it probably will
用几片叶子，它可能会
in a typical sorting algorithm.
在典型的排序算法中。
And how many possible answers are there?
有多少可能的答案？
Batter?
面糊？
AUDIENCE: n factorial.
听众：n阶乘。
PROFESSOR: n factorial, number of permutations.
教授：n阶乘，排列数。
This is a permutation of the input sequence
这是输入序列的排列
and if all the items you're given are distinct,
如果所有给您的物品都是不同的，
there will be n factorial permutations of them.
他们将有n个阶乘排列。
So that's the worst case.
所以那是最坏的情况。
So n factorial.
所以n阶乘。
Now the tricky part is the algebra.
现在最棘手的部分是代数。
Say, oh, well then the height is at least
说，哦，那么高度至少是
lg base 2 of n factorial-- lg base 2
n因数的lg基数2-lg基数2
because it's a binary tree.
因为它是一棵二叉树。
You can put a parentheses here if you want,
如果需要，可以在此处加上括号，
they're not necessary.
他们不是必需的。
So now I want to claim that this is n lg n.
因此，现在我想宣称这是n lg n。
How do I do that?
我怎么做？
Maybe you just know?
也许你只是知道？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: We can either use Stirling's approximation
听众：我们可以使用斯特林近似
or we could write it out as a sum [INAUDIBLE]
或者我们可以将其写成一笔[音频不清晰]
PROFESSOR: Wow, cool.
教授：哇，好酷。
All right, you could either use Stirling's approximation
好吧，您可以使用斯特林近似
or write it out as a sum.
或将其写出。
I've never done it with it sum.
我从来没有这样做过。
Let's do that, that sounds like fun.
让我们这样做，听起来很有趣。
So, right?
这样吧
I like that because you know Stirling's-- it's like
我喜欢那是因为你知道斯特林的-就像
you've got to know Stirling and that's kind of annoying.
您必须了解斯特灵，这很烦人。
What if you don't know Sterling?
如果您不知道英镑怎么办？
But we all know the definition of factorial.
但是我们都知道阶乘的定义。
I mean, we learned in grade school
我的意思是我们在小学学习
just because it's fun, right?
只是因为它很有趣，对不对？
Oh, I guess we-- I mean we did because we're geeks.
哦，我想我们-我的意思是我们这样做是因为我们是极客。
And then we know the lg of our product is the sum of the lg's.
然后我们知道我们产品的lg是lg的总和。
So this is lg n plus lg n minus 1 plus lg 2 plus lg 1.
因此，这是lg n加lg n减去1加lg 2加上lg 1。
I think at this point it's easier
我认为在这一点上比较容易
to use summation notation, so sum of lg i.
使用求和符号，所以lg i的总和。
OK now we've got to do sum, this is 1 to n I guess.
好的，现在我们必须进行求和，我猜是1到n。
Now we need to know something about lg's, so it's not
现在我们需要了解有关lg的一些知识，所以这不是
so easy.
太简单。
It's easy to show-- I mean, certainly this is at most n lg
很容易显示-我的意思是，这肯定是最多n lg
n, but we need show that it's at least n lg n.
n，但我们需要证明它至少为n lg n。
That's a little trickier.
有点棘手。
I happen to know it's true.
我碰巧知道这是真的。
But I'd know it even in the summation form
但是即使以总和的形式我也知道
because I know that lg-- lg looks like this basically,
因为我知道lg-- lg基本上是这样的，
and so if you're adding up, you're
所以如果你加起来，你就是
taking the area under this curve right?
取这条曲线下的面积正确吗？
Oh, look at these integrals.
哦，看看这些积分。
Oh, integrals.
哦，积分。
Brings back memories.
带回回忆。
This is discrete math class, though, continuous stuff.
但是，这是离散的数学课，是连续的东西。
So you're adding up all these numbers, right?
所以您要将所有这些数字加起来，对不对？
This is lg i over all the i's and basically all of them
这是我所有的lg我，基本上都是
have the same length.
具有相同的长度。
Like if you look at the last half, that
就像你看最后一半一样
would be one way to prove it.
将是证明它的一种方法。
Ah, it's fun, haven't done summations in so long.
啊，很有趣，很久没做总结了。
Good stuff. [? IS042 ?] material but applied to algorithms
好东西。 [？ IS042？]材料，但已应用于算法
and in algorithms it's fun because you could throw away
在算法中，它很有趣，因为您可以扔掉
constant factors and life is good.
不变的因素，生活是美好的。
We don't need exact answers really.
我们真的不需要确切的答案。
You can find an exact answer, but let's say
您可以找到确切的答案，但可以说
you look at the last half.
你看看最后一半。
Those are all going to be basically lg n.
这些基本上都是lg n。
You can prove that.
您可以证明这一点。
So this is going to be at least the sum where
所以这至少是总和
i equals n over 2 n of lg i.
我等于lg i的2 n中的n。
Here I just throw away the first out of our two terms.
在这里，我只是放弃了我们两个任期中的第一个。
And this is going to be at least sum i equals n over 2
这将至少等于和2
to n of lg n over 2.
到lg n中的n大于2。
Each of these terms is bigger than lg n over 2
这些项中的每一项都大于lg n> 2
so if I just say, well, they're all lg n over 2 that's
所以如果我只是说，嗯，他们都是lg n over 2，那就是
going to give me something even smaller.
会给我更小的东西。
Now the lg n over 2, that's just lg n minus 1.
现在lg n大于2，也就是lg n减1。
I love this.
我喜欢这个。
It's going to give the right answer even.
它甚至可以给出正确的答案。
So that's an equals and so this equals n lg n minus n.
所以这是一个等于，所以等于n lg n减去n。
That summation I can do.
我可以做的总结。
All the terms are the same, sorry n over 2.
所有条款都相同，对不起，请超过2。
Not quite what I wanted.
不完全是我想要的。
Close enough.
足够近。
Sorry there is only n over 2 terms
抱歉，只有n个词超过2个词
here, ignoring floors and ceilings.
在这里，忽略了地板和天花板。
So I get n lg n divided by 2.
所以我得到n lg n除以2。
This is omega n lg n because this n term
这是omega n lg n，因为这n个项
is smaller than n lg n.
小于n lg n。
So this one dominates.
因此，这一主导。
Doesn't matter if this one's negative, because it's smaller.
否定的也没关系，因为它较小。
This is omega n lg n.
这是欧米茄。
We're done.
大功告成
Sorting is omega n lg n.
排序为。
Very easy.
很容易。
Who said summations?
谁说总结？
All right.
好吧。
Why don't you come collect a pillow,
你为什么不来收集枕头
I'm not going to throw that far.
我不会扔那么远。
Afterwards.
然后。
OK.
好。
That's one way to do it.
那是做到这一点的一种方法。
Another way to do it, if you happen
如果发生的话，另一种方法
to know Stirling's formula for n factorial-- n factorial
知道n阶乘n阶乘的斯特林公式
is about n over e to the n times square root of 2 pi n.
在e上大约n等于2 pi n的n平方根。
Right?
对？
If you do Taylor series approximation of n factorial,
如果对n因数进行泰勒级数逼近，
the first term, which is the most important term for us
第一学期，对我们来说是最重要的学期
because as the asymptotically dominating
因为作为渐近支配
term is square root of 2 pi n times n over e to the n.
项是2 pi n乘以e到n的平方根。
Hope I got that right.
希望我说对了。
Yeah, clearly I've been studying.
是的，显然我一直在学习。
You take lg's of that and you do the same thing of lg
你拿lg的，你做lg的同样的事情
of a product is sum of the lg's and you end up
一个产品的总和就是lg的总和
with-- the right answer is actually n lg n minus order n.
正确的答案实际上是n lg n减去n。
So I was off by a factor of 2 here.
所以我在这里差了2倍。
The linear term-- it does appear,
线性项-它确实出现了，
but it's smaller than this and this is also omega n lg n.
但它比这还小，也是Ωn lg n。
If you don't care about constants, it doesn't matter.
如果您不关心常量，那就没关系。
If you care about constants, the constant is 1.
如果您关心常量，则常量为1。
Kind of nice.
有点不错。
Easy to prove a one half.
容易证明一半。
And if you look at the lecture notes it works through that.
而且，如果您看一下讲义，它就可以正常工作。
But I think we've seen enough of that lower bound.
但是我认为我们已经看到了足够多的下限。
And that's the end of our lower bound topic.
至此，我们的下限主题结束了。
Any questions on that?
有什么问题吗？
So it's really easy.
因此，这真的很容易。
Once you set up this framework of comparison trees and now
一旦建立了比较树的框架，现在
it becomes just a question of the height of a comparison
只是比较高度的问题
tree.
树。
Comparison trees are binary.
比较树是二进制的。
Just count how many leaves do you have to have,
只要算出你必须有多少叶子，
take lg of that and you get a lower bound of that.
取lg的那个，就会得到一个下限。
AUDIENCE: What is meant by n preprocessed items?
听众：n个预处理物品是什么意思？
PROFESSOR: Oh, yeah.
教授：哦，是的。
For searching I was trying to be careful and say, well,
为了进行搜索，我试图小心一点，说，
if I have n preprocessed items.
如果我有n个预处理项目。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: It means you can do whatever the heck you want.
教授：这意味着您可以做任何想做的事情。
So here's the model.
这是模型。
I give you n items.
我给你n件。
You can do all pairwise comparisons between those items
您可以在这些项目之间进行所有成对比较
for free and then I give you a new item
免费，然后我给你一个新项目
and then I start charging for comparisons.
然后我开始收费以进行比较。
So another way to say it is I only
所以另一种说法是我只
charge between for comparisons between x and the other items.
在x和其他项目之间进行比较时收取费用。
And even then you need lg n.
即使这样，您也需要lg n。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] case for sorting, right?
听众：[听不清]整理箱，对不对？
PROFESSOR: With sorting they were not preprocessed.
教授：经过排序，它们没有经过预处理。
Yeah, I didn't write the theorem.
是的，我没有写定理。
It's just sorting and given items, no preprocessing.
它只是排序和给定项目，无需预处理。
AUDIENCE: What if there were preprocessing?
听众：如果进行预处理会怎样？
PROFESSOR: If they were preprocessed,
教授：如果他们已经过预处理，
you'd be done in zero comparisons.
您将完成零比较。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，完全正确。
This theorem is also true if I remove preprocessed,
如果我删除预处理，这个定理也成立，
but in fact then you need n time.
但实际上，您需要n次。
Unfortunately this proof technique
不幸的是，这种证明技术
will only prove a lower bound of log n,
只会证明log n的下限，
because even if these items were not preprocessed, then
因为即使这些项目没有经过预处理，
you have to do linear search basically.
您必须基本上进行线性搜索。
So if you don't know anything about the items,
因此，如果您对这些物品一无所知，
you need linear time.
您需要线性时间。
But this proof will only prove a lower bound of log n.
但是此证明只能证明log n的下限。
So this technique, while cool and simple,
因此，这项技术虽然简单又酷，
does not always give you the right answer.
并不总是能给您正确的答案。
It just gives you a lower bound.
它只是给您一个下限。
May not be the right lower bound, may not be tight.
可能不是正确的下限，可能不是严格的。
So searching always requires lg n time and what's interesting
所以搜索总是需要lg n时间，而有趣的是
is it requires it even when you preprocess the items.
即使在预处理项目时也需要它吗？
Sorting, if you haven't preprocessed the items,
排序，如果您尚未预处理项目，
then it takes n lg n.
则需要n lg n。
Clear?
明确？
Good.
好。
Now we get to the algorithms part of the lecture, always
现在，我们总是去讲课的算法部分
the most fun.
最有趣的。
The moments you've been waiting for.
您一直在等待的时刻。
Let me erase comparison trees.
让我删除比较树。
Henceforth and I mean not only this lecture, but also
从今以后，我的意思不仅是这次演讲，
the next three lectures which are about hashing,
接下来的三讲是关于散列的
we will not be in the comparison model
我们将不在比较模型中
because for comparison model, we're done.
因为对于比较模型，我们已经完成了。
We solved search, we solved sorting, n lg n three ways.
我们解决了搜索，我们解决了排序，三种方式。
I mean, how much more can we do?
我的意思是，我们还能做什么？
So it's time to bump it up a notch,
现在是时候把它提高一个档次了，
increase our model power.
增加我们的模型能力。
We've talked about the RAM in particular, Random Access
我们特别讨论了RAM，即随机存取
Machine, where memory is in array,
机器，内存在阵列中，
you can access anything in the array in constant time.
您可以在恒定时间内访问数组中的任何内容。
We're going to use that power of the RAM to sort in linear time,
我们将使用RAM的功能来按线性时间排序，
sometimes.
有时。
A more appropriate title for this section of this lecture
本课本节的更合适的标题
would be integer sorting.
将是整数排序。
OK, so far we've been talking about comparison
好，到目前为止，我们一直在谈论比较
sorting where the items you're given-- the only thing you
排序您在哪里得到的物品-您唯一的选择
know about them is that you can compare them in constant time.
了解它们是您可以在恒定时间内进行比较。
But now we're going to think about the situation
但是现在我们要考虑情况
where the things that you're sorting are integers.
您要排序的是整数。
That's a big assumption but it's a practical assumption a lot
这是一个很大的假设，但实际上是一个实际的假设
of the time.
的时间。
If you're not sorting integers you can map whatever the heck
如果您不对整数进行排序，则可以映射任何内容
you're sorting into integers.
您正在将整数排序。
And usually it's already been done
通常已经完成了
because you're representing it on a computer.
因为您是在计算机上表示它。
You've already represented your thing is an integer of sorts.
您已经表示自己的事情是各种各样的整数。
Bad pun.
双关语。
This is an assumption.
这是一个假设。
So we assume-- going to be a little more precise.
因此，我们假设-会更加精确。
The keys you're sorting are integers.
您要排序的键是整数。
There's still-- I'm going to put a little n here,
还有-我要在这里放一点n
remember there's n keys.
记得有n把钥匙。
I'm also going to assume that they're in some range.
我还要假设它们在一定范围内。
And for convenience, I'm going to assume that they're all
为了方便起见，我将假设它们都是
non-negative-- it's not hard to deal with negative numbers,
非负数-处理负数并不难，
but it's just convenient to think
但是思考起来很方便
about non-negative numbers.
关于非负数。
So if you start at zero, there's some maximum value,
因此，如果您从零开始，那么会有一些最大值，
say k minus 1.
说k减1。
So there's k different values they could be.
因此，它们可能有k个不同的值。
K could be anything.
K可以是任何东西。
It's a parameter.
这是一个参数。
We've always had n as a parameter,
我们一直都有n作为参数，
now we're going to also have k as a parameter.
现在我们还将以k为参数。
And just for completeness-- and each fits in a word.
只是为了完整性-每个词都适合一个词。
Remember the machine word of your RAM machine?
还记得您的RAM机器的机器字吗？
Words were the things that we could
言语是我们可以做的事
manipulate in constant time.
在恒定时间内进行操作。
Now this is a very reasonable assumption
现在，这是一个非常合理的假设
because we've been assuming so far
因为到目前为止我们一直在假设
you can compare two keys to items in constant time.
您可以在固定时间内将两个键与项目进行比较。
To get that for integers, you need
要获取整数，您需要
to assume that your integers are fitting in words.
假设您的整数适合单词。
We usually don't state this assumption,
我们通常不陈述这个假设，
but I thought I'd throw it in just for kicks.
但是我以为我会踢它。
So we've got a bunch of integers,
所以我们有一堆整数，
each one fits in a word.
每个单词都适合。
I could compare them, that takes constant time,
我可以比较一下，这需要持续的时间，
or I could add them or subtract them or multiply them or divide
或者我可以将它们相加或相减或相乘或相除
them or do whatever the heck I want.
他们或做我想要的一切。
It turns out you can do a lot more than comparisons
事实证明，您所要做的不只是比较
and it turns out this will help us.
事实证明，这将对我们有所帮助。
I don't know if I want to tell you the answer here.
我不知道是否要在这里告诉你答案。
For k-- not too big-- you can sort in linear time.
对于k-不太大-可以按线性时间排序。
Believe it or not, this topic, integer sorting,
信不信由你，这个主题，整数排序，
is still a major area of research.
仍然是主要的研究领域。
People are still trying to solve this problem.
人们仍在努力解决这个问题。
One conjecture is that even in all cases,
一个猜想是，即使在所有情况下，
you can sort in linear time given
您可以按照给定的线性时间进行排序
any integers that fit in words.
任何适合单词的整数。
This is not yet solved.
这还没有解决。
Best algorithm is n times square root lg lg
最佳算法是n次平方根lg lg
n with high probability.
n的概率很高。
So it's almost-- almost n.
所以几乎-几乎是n。
It's a lot better than n lg n.
比n lg n好很多。
I'll just write that for fun case you can't parse in words.
我只是写一个有趣的例子，你不能用语言来解析。
This is the best algorithms to date.
这是迄今为止最好的算法。
I would conjecture you can do linear time in all situations.
我猜想你可以在所有情况下做线性时间。
We're not going to cover this algorithm.
我们将不讨论该算法。
That's a little beyond us.
那超出了我们。
It's in advanced algorithms if you're interested, 6854.
如果您有兴趣，可以使用高级算法6854。
But we're going to show that for a lot of cases of interest
但是我们将展示很多感兴趣的案例
when k is not ginormous, it's really
当k不是巨大的时候
easy to sort in linear time.
易于按线性时间排序。
All right?
好吧？
And our first algorithm to achieve this is counting sort.
我们实现此目标的第一个算法是计数排序。
Counting sort does not make any comparisons.
计数排序不做任何比较。
It only does other stuff.
它只做其他事情。
And it's going to depend on n.
这将取决于n。
It's going to depend on k.
这将取决于k。
We'll get some running times not bad as long as k is not giant.
只要k不大，我们将获得一些不错的运行时间。
So as the name might suggest, what you
顾名思义，您会
do is count all the items.
要做的就是计算所有项目。
So imagine I give you a bunch of keys like 3, 5 7, 5, 5, 3, 6,
想象一下，我给你一堆钥匙，例如3、5、7、5、5、3、6
whatever.
随你。
I'd like to run through this array
我想遍历这个数组
and say, ah, I see there are two 3's and there
说，啊，我看到有两个3
are three 5's and there's one 6, and one 7, so how do I sort it?
有3个5，有1个6和1个7，那么如何排序呢？
I'd like to say, well 3 is smallest key
我想说，3是最小键
and there's two of them, so I'll write two 3's, then there's
有两个，所以我写两个3，然后有
three 5's so I'll write three 5's, and then there's a 6
三个5，所以我写三个5，然后有一个6
and then there's a 7.
然后是7
That's the intuition.
这是直觉。
Now how do I-- how I do that with an algorithm?
现在我该如何使用算法来做到这一点？
Suggestions?
有什么建议吗？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Allocate an array of memory, which
分配一个内存数组，
is my counters-- I'm going to count each k.
是我的计数器-我要计数每个k。
I need an array of size k because there
我需要一个大小为k的数组，因为
are k possible keys.
是k个可能的键。
Convenient those two terms start with the same letter.
方便的是，这两个术语以相同的字母开头。
And then I'll just-- whenever I see
然后我会-每当我看到
an-- I'm going to run through the items in order,
一个-我将按顺序浏览这些项目，
when I see an item, I say, OK, well that's key 3.
当我看到一个项目时，我说，好，那是关键3。
I will look at index 3 of this array, increment that counter.
我将看一下该数组的索引3，增加该计数器。
Then I see 5, increment that counter.
然后我看到5，增加那个计数器。
I see 7, I see 5, I see 5, and by the end,
我看到7，我看到5，我看到5，最后，
I'll know that there are three 5's and two 3's and so on.
我会知道有三个5和两个3，依此类推。
That's how I count.
我就是这样计算的。
And then how do output the items?
然后如何输出项目？
You want to keep going?
你想继续吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Yeah, just traverse the array
教授：是的，只需遍历数组
of counters and the array is already
的计数器和数组已经
written in order by key, so it's really easy.
按键顺序编写，因此非常容易。
I mean I could draw this array for you if you like at 0, 1,
我的意思是，如果您喜欢0、1，我可以为您绘制此数组
2 3.
2 3。
Here's the 3 position, it ends up with the value 2.
这是第3个位置，其最终值为2。
And if I just go through, a lot of these will have 0's in them,
如果我刚讲完，其中很多将带有0，
just skip those.
只是跳过那些。
When I find a non-zero entry, just
当我发现一个非零条目时，
write-- oh, that means there's two 3's there, so I write 3, 3.
写-哦，那意味着那里有两个3，所以我写3、3。
OK, that algorithm would work but I'm not
好的，该算法可以工作，但我不能
going to even write it down, not even going to dignify it,
甚至要写下来，甚至不去端庄
because all it does is sort integers.
因为它所做的只是对整数排序。
But there's a subtlety here which
但是这里有一个微妙之处
we're going to need in a moment, which is why I stress it,
我们很快就会需要，这就是我强调它的原因，
that really we have n items.
确实我们有n个项目。
Each of them has a key, but it might have other stuff
他们每个人都有一个钥匙，但可能还有其他东西
too that we'd like to bring along for the ride.
我们也想带他去兜风。
We'll see why we care about that in a moment.
我们一会儿就会明白为什么我们会在意这一点。
But it's also a typical situation,
但这也是典型的情况
like you have a spreadsheet and you click sort by this column.
就像您有一个电子表格，然后单击“按此列排序”。
Well every row has a whole bunch of data
好每一行都有一堆数据
but you're only trying to sort by one of those fields,
但您仅尝试按这些字段之一进行排序，
that one column.
那一栏。
And that one field may be an integer,
而且一个字段可以是整数，
but there's all this other stuff you'd like to bring along.
但是还有其他所有您想带的东西。
And when you say, oh, there are two 3's,
当你说，哦，有两个3
you know there's this 3, which you know maybe
你知道这是3，你也许知道
has a cloud around it.
周围有云。
There's this 3 which maybe has a heart around it.
这3个周围可能有一颗心。
That's about the limit of my drawing abilities.
那是我绘画能力的极限。
And now say, oh, there are two 3's but which 3?
现在说，哦，有两个3，但是哪个3？
Should the cloud go first, should the heart go first?
云应该先走，心要先走吗？
I mean I don't care which goes first,
我的意思是我不在乎哪个先行
maybe-- I do, actually-- but I will in a moment.
也许-实际上，但是-稍后我会。
That's another topic.
那是另一个话题。
But I'd like to bring that cloud somewhere.
但是我想把那朵云带到某个地方。
I want to put the cloud somewhere,
我想把云放在某个地方，
want to put the heart somewhere.
想把心放在某处。
All right, so here's a way to do all that.
好的，这是完成所有操作的一种方法。
Basically the same algorithm but I'm just going to use lists.
基本上是相同的算法，但我将使用列表。
Still have an array of k things but no longer counters,
仍然有k个东西数组，但不再有计数器，
now lists.
现在列出。
They could be linked lists, they could be python lists.
它们可以是链接列表，也可以是python列表。
It won't matter for my purposes.
对我而言，这无关紧要。
And then I'll say for j and range of n-- that'd
然后我要说出j和n的范围
be super pythonic here-- I want to look at the list who's
在这里超级pythonic-我想看看谁的名单
at index a of j and append a of j.
在j的索引a处并追加j的a。
And then the output is going to be an empty list initially.
然后输出最初将是一个空列表。
And then I iterate through the array their k values for that,
然后我遍历数组中的k值，
and I just say output, extend, list i.
我只是说输出，扩展，列出我。
OK.
好。
This is counting sort or a version of counting sort.
这是计数排序或计数排序的一种版本。
In your textbook, you'll find a different version which
在教科书中，您会找到其他版本，
does not use lists, So it's probably more practical
不使用列表，所以它可能更实用
because it uses no data structures whatsoever
因为它不使用任何数据结构
except three arrays.
除了三个数组。
But it runs in the same amount of time
但是它运行的时间相同
and this is a lot easier I think to think about.
我想这要容易得多。
This is more modern perspective, if you well.
如果您愿意的话，这是更现代的观点。
For every item, if you'd look at them
对于每个项目，如果您要看一下
in the given order of your array,
按照数组的给定顺序，
you see what it's key value is.
您会看到它的关键价值是什么。
Maybe that's not exactly the same as the item,
可能与商品不完全相同，
so it could be key of x is just x.
所以可能x的键只是x。
But you know in python sort, for example,
但是您知道python排序
you're given a key function.
您会获得关键功能。
So you take that key value.
因此，您可以获取关键价值。
The key is guaranteed to be an integer between 0
该键保证是0到0之间的整数
and k minus 1, so you look at the list, that numbered list,
和k减1，所以您查看列表，该编号列表，
and you just add this item to the list.
然后您只需将此项目添加到列表中即可。
OK.
好。
But the item is not just the key,
但是，这不仅仅是关键，
it's everything-- whatever that data structure is--
一切-无论数据结构是什么-
and then you just go through the list and you concatenate them.
然后您只需浏览列表，然后将它们连接起来。
OK.
好。
How long does this take?
这需要多长时间？
How long does this step take?
此步骤需要多长时间？
N?
不行
Nope.
不。
Constant?
不变？
Nope.
不。
OK.
好。
Look at all the actions.
查看所有动作。
It's order k time.
这是k时间。
To create an empty list takes constant time.
创建一个空列表需要固定的时间。
They're k of them.
他们是其中的k。
OK?
好？
How long does this step take, just the append?
仅需追加，此步骤需要多长时间？
Constant?
不变？
Good.
好。
Remember, append is constant time from the Python model
请记住，append是Python模型中的固定时间
or your favorite model, anything.
或您最喜欢的模型，任何东西。
We're assuming the key takes constant time
我们假设密钥需要固定的时间
because that's the word, so that's an assumption,
因为那是单词，所以这是一个假设，
but in the normal assumption.
但按照正常的假设。
So total time here is order n.
因此，这里的总时间为n。
And this thing, well this takes basically the length
而这件事，这基本上需要花费时间
of Li time.
李时间。
And so when you add it up, maybe plus 1--
因此，当您将其相加时，可能会加上1--
because to look at an empty list you still
因为要看一个空清单，你仍然
need to look at it-- so you add it up
需要看看-所以您将其加起来
and you get order sum of all the Li's is all the items.
您会得到所有李氏物品的订单总和。
And then you get plus 1 for each of them,
然后您每个人加1，
so you get n plus k. n plus k is the running
所以你得到n加k n加k正在运行
time of this algorithm.
该算法的时间。
Add those up.
加起来
OK, so counting sort is order n plus k.
好的，所以计数排序是n加上k。
So if k happens to be order n, this is linear time.
因此，如果k恰好是n阶，则这是线性时间。
But as soon as it's a little bit bigger, you're in trouble.
但是，只要稍大一点，您就会遇到麻烦。
So counting sort's a good warm up,
所以算是一个很好的热身，
but it's not ultimately what we want.
但这并不是我们最终想要的。
And a much cooler algorithm is called radix sort.
而且更酷的算法称为基数排序。
It's going to use counting sort as the subroutine, which
它将使用计数排序作为子例程，
is why spent all this time on a mediocre algorithm.
这就是为什么将所有这些时间都花在平庸的算法上的原因。
And it's going to get a much larger range of k
而且它将获得更大范围的k
and it will still be linear time.
而且仍然是线性时间。
I'll tell you the answer.
我会告诉你答案。
K can be polynomial in n.
K可以是n中的多项式。
So like if all your integers are between 0 and n to the 100,
因此，就像所有整数都在0到n到100之间一样，
you can sort them in n lg n time.
您可以n n n次对它们进行排序。
That's a lot bigger.
更大了。
It's not just like 10 n.
不只是10 n。
I mean you could do 10 n here as well with counting sort.
我的意思是您也可以在这里进行10 n计数排序。
And it's not just like n lg n, but they can go all the way
这不仅仅像n lg n，而且他们可以一路走下去
to n to the 100, still be linear time.
到n到100，仍然是线性时间。
So that's what we're going to achieve.
这就是我们要实现的目标。
The idea of radix sort is simple.
基数排序的想法很简单。
It's actually kind of the Excel spreadsheet approach.
实际上，这是一种Excel电子表格方法。
We're going to imagine we want to break
我们将想象我们要打破
each integer into a bunch of columns.
每个整数变成一列列。
How do we do that?
我们该怎么做？
Well, the way we normally write down numbers,
好吧，我们通常写下数字的方式，
except not necessarily in decimal, in some arbitrary base
除非不一定是十进制，否则可以是任意基数
b.
b。
So I say, oh, an integer in base b.
所以我说，哦，以b为底的整数。
Well then there's the least significant digit
好吧，那是最不重要的数字
and then the next one and the next one
然后下一个和下一个
and the next one, some sequence of digits.
下一个是一些数字序列。
And if I know that the maximum value is k,
如果我知道最大值是k
I know that the number of digits,
我知道位数
which I'm going to call-- for each number which I'm
我要打电话给我的每个号码
going to call d, is just lg base b of k plus one, whatever.
将要呼叫d，只是lg以b为基础的k加1，无论如何。
We've got to be super precise here
我们必须在这里非常精确
because if I'm in base b then that's what lg is, right?
因为如果我在基地b中，那就是lg，对吗？
So normally we think of lg base 2
所以通常我们想到lg base 2
because we're writing things in binary.
因为我们用二进制编写东西。
Computer scientists normally think that way.
计算机科学家通常以这种方式思考。
And fine, so now we decomposed our integer.
很好，所以现在我们分解整数。
I'm not going to actually compute this base
我不会实际计算这个基数
b representation, because it would take a long time.
b表示，因为需要很长时间。
I'd have to spend n times lg k time to do that.
我必须花n倍于lg k的时间来做到这一点。
I don't want to do that.
我不想那样做。
OK, but just imagine it that way.
好的，但是就这样想吧。
And then the algorithm as follows,
然后算法如下
sort the integers, all of them, by the least significant digit.
将所有整数按最低有效位排序。
Sort by the next least significant digit.
按下一个最低有效数字排序。
Dot, dot, dot, sort by the most significant digit.
点，点，点按最高有效位排序。
So there are d iterations here, for d digits.
因此，这里有d个迭代，即d个数字。
Sort all the integers by the least significant,
将所有整数按最低有效位排序，
all the integers by the next, and so on.
所有整数乘以下一个，依此类推。
It's like in your-- this is a useful technique in Excel,
就像在您中，这是Excel中的一项有用技术，
if you want to sort by several columns--
如果您要按几列进行排序，
or your favorite spreadsheet, doesn't have to be Excel,
或您最喜欢的电子表格，不必是Excel，
sorry-- you click on the least significant column first,
抱歉-您先点击最低有效列，
and then click on all the other columns in increasing order,
然后按升序单击所有其他列，
you will sort by all of them, it turns out.
事实证明，您将对它们进行排序。
It's kind of magical that this works.
这种方法有点神奇。
I don't have a ton of time for an example.
我没有很多时间来举例说明。
Let me first analyze the algorithm.
首先让我分析一下算法。
We'll see if we have time for an example.
我们将看看是否有时间举例。
So there are d digits-- oh, and I'm
所以有d位数字-哦，我
going to sort each of these sorts of using counting sort.
将要使用计数排序对所有这些排序。
This is I guess sort by digit using counting sort.
我想这是使用计数排序按数字排序。
So how long does it take to sort using
所以使用排序需要多长时间
counting sort in this setting?
在这种情况下计数排序？
Normally, it's n plus k.
通常，它是n加k。
Here it is, n plus b.
在这里，n加b。
Good.
好。
Because all of our digits are between 0 and b minus 1.
因为我们所有的数字都在0到b减去1之间。
So we're just sorting by digit.
所以我们只是按数字排序。
Now here is where we're using this idea of a key.
现在，这里是我们使用密钥的想法的地方。
When we say key, I wanted our integers.
当我们说密钥时，我想要我们的整数。
What we do is compute the digit we care about.
我们要做的是计算我们关心的数字。
So if we're in this step, the key function
所以如果我们在这一步，关键功能
will be compute the least significant digit, which
将计算最低有效位，即
is like taking it mod b to compute the most
就像用mod b计算最多
significant digits like dividing by b to the power of d minus 1
有效数字，例如用b除以d的幂减去1
or so.
或者。
OK but it's a constant.
好的，但这是一个常数。
You do one divide and one mod, the constant number
你做一除一模，常数
of operations.
操作。
You can extract the digit in constant time.
您可以在固定时间内提取数字。
So the key function is constant time and so this works.
因此关键功能是恒定时间，因此可以正常工作。
We don't have to actually write them all down,
我们不必把它们全部写下来，
just compute them as we need them.
只需根据需要计算它们。
Cool I guess we could compute them ahead of time.
太酷了，我想我们可以提前计算它们。
It's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
Fine.
精细。
So that's each digit.
这就是每个数字。
So the total time is just that times
所以总时间就是那个时间
d because we have d steps.
d因为我们有d个步骤。
So it's n plus b times d.
所以它是n加b乘以d。
Now d was that lg thing, lg base b of n.
现在d是那个lg物，n的lg基b。
I have this b.
我有这个b。
What should be b?
b应该是什么？
You gotta love the English language.
你一定喜欢英语。
What should I choose b to be, or not to be?
我应该选择b作为还是不成为？
That's the question.
这就是问题所在。
Any suggestions?
有什么建议么？
I want to minimize this, right?
我想最小化这个，对吗？
I want minimum running time.
我想要最短的运行时间。
So I'd like b to kind of large to make this base large.
因此，我希望b较大以使此基准较大。
Sorry, this is not n, this is k.
抱歉，这不是n，是k。
I copied that wrong out of excitement.
我激动地复制了那个错误。
Just copying this over.
只需将其复制过来。
OK, I'd like b to be large, but I
好吧，我希望b变大，但是我
don't want it to be so large because I don't want
不想这么大，因为我不想
it to be bigger than n so what should I set b to be?
它大于n，那么我应该将b设置为什么？
AUDIENCE: N.
听众：N.
PROFESSOR: N, good choice.
教授：N，不错的选择。
It's a good trick whenever you have
每当你有一个好把戏
a sum of things you want to minimize,
您想减少的总和，
usually it's when they're equal.
通常是在他们平等的时候。
Occasionally it's the extreme like when b is 0 or something.
有时就像b为0或类似的东西时那样极端。
B as 0 not a good plan.
B设为0并不是一个好计划。
Base 0 is pretty slow.
以0为底的速度非常慢。
So if I set-- I'll write it here--
因此，如果我设置-我将在这里写下-
you can prove it with a derivative or whatever.
您可以用导数或其他方式证明这一点。
This is going to be minimized when
这将被最小化
b is-- I'll be vague-- theta n.
b是-我会含糊-theta n。
So then it's going to come out to n times lg base n of k.
因此，它将以k的n为lg的n倍。
And lo and behold, when k is polynomial in n,
瞧，当k是n的多项式时，
it's k to some constant, then that will be linear.
它是k到某个常数，那么它将是线性的。
So let me write that.
所以，让我写下来。
If k equals n to the c, or say is at most n to the c,
如果k等于c的n，或者说c等于n，
then this is going to be order n times c.
那么这将是n次c。
So if your integers are reasonably small,
因此，如果您的整数相当小，
you get a linear time sorting algorithm.
您将获得线性时间排序算法。
And reasonably small means polynomial in n, in value.
较小的值表示n中的多项式。
That's kind of cool.
太酷了。
That's radix sort.
这是基数排序。
And we're out of time.
而且我们没时间了。
There's an example in the textbook
教科书中有一个例子
or in the notes how this works.
或在注释中这是如何工作的。
You could prove it by a simple induction.
您可以通过简单的归纳证明。